hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft now
today's episode is actually going to be
a little bit shorter than usual due to a
bunch of circumstances that has left me
very short of time basically a bunch of
projects fell through and or have been
delayed and i haven't had my usual time
to make a hermitcraft video i normally
spend about three days in total making
each episode
but today i have barely a few hours
anyway let's crack on with what we want
to do today so as you can see i've kind
of made a hole here i was thinking
the only way to get up to the top of
this building right now is to fly there
and that's not going to do anymore i'm
afraid i really need just a quick way up
to save myself some rockets so i was
thinking we're gonna make a water
elevator up here but
these towers which everybody's been
complaining about are not finished
please please please don't complain
about how ugly and bland the towers are
they're not finished and you're probably
gonna think they look even worse after
this little segment because i'm gonna do
a quick time lapse of me building these
towers
all the way to the top and i mean all
the way to the top we go to the absolute
build limit in this one so let's crack
on with it
as with all of my time lapses on
hermitcraft i'm going to use this time
to answer some of your questions paul
lloyd asked have you got the whole
season planned or are you making it up
as you go or a mixture of both i would
say definitely the former i definitely
haven't got anything planned i'm making
it up as i go along however i do have a
few ideas that i do have in mind but i'm
not prepared to do yet due to resources
or time or i need to get set up and
stuff there's more stuff to do in the
future but i'm mainly making it up as i
go along sri girl i'm sorry if i
butchered that name when do you plan to
take that mustache away i saw a few
questions very similar to this i have
constantly well not constantly a few
times mentioned that i'm going to be
taking mumbo's mustache away and i'm
pleased to tell you that that time is
coming up very very shortly however i do
need to get a base down because it
involves a very specific build that i
need to make and here's the great bit i
need mumbo's help in order to make it
i'll leave it at that for now we'll get
there
it's woofles says when will you start
uploading on green2 now green2 is a
second channel that i made public and
attached it to my channel but i haven't
uploaded anything on it i haven't done
anything serious with it i don't really
have many plans with it i thought it
would be a great place to also dump
videos that wouldn't go on the main
channel
or videos that kind of suffer on the
main channel so for example vlogs
usually don't do too well and for some
reason you guys have been subscribing to
it like crazy it has 17 000 subscribers
and i haven't done anything so i guess
thank you if i can get it to 100k i i
really just need to make some videos on
it anyway let's get back into
hermitcraft
so
that
was a huge amount of resources thousands
and thousands of blocks went into this
there is 11 blocks between each one and
i did exactly as i explained last
episode with my plan it does look a
little bit like the burj khalifa
but
i think it looks pretty cool obviously
this middle bit is empty
but it's not finished yet we actually
need to fill this in and i have a few
ideas that i'm going to sort of run past
everybody but boy oh boy this is tall
it's maybe
too tall it does look really really
impressive especially when you're down
below here
it is it has got some sort of majestic
aspect to it so here i'm going to ignore
this this was a little experiment that's
now gone wrong so
i'm thinking here we're going to have
another circle maybe not a full layer
like the ones beneath me but a mini one
unfortunately i've already built these
towels in place so doing this completely
symmetrically is probably gonna
not work out too well so i'm gonna
create another circle probably about
this high
what i'm thinking is this
circle here is going to wrap around
maybe to about this height here and then
this circle you see on that will sit on
the top of it so in theory
it's going to go to about here and then
it's going to finish around there this
little bubble here will end up being
there and i'm thinking right up here
right in the center we create our nether
portal this is gonna be the official
nether entrance to my base and i was
thinking of maybe situating it inside an
orb i think that would be really cool
and i really hope that this will come
together because you never really know
with these kind of builds it's very
difficult i'm so out of my comfort zone
here i just i don't know
exactly what i'm doing freestyling a
build and i know that if i was gonna do
this entire build again i would do a lot
of things very very differently my
problem is at the moment that i keep
getting distracted by little projects as
i'm doing them so if i'm working on one
layer i kind of get bored or i run out
of resources like i have done just now
and then i start working on something
else leaving it in its very unfinished
state but we're going to continue the
time lapse on this at some point in the
future because i want you guys to see
the progress that's going on here for
each tower they're not going to remain
in their bland state they're going to
have little decorations in them in fact
some of it might have like a bit taken
out of it and then it will have some
cyan terracotta or concrete in there to
give it a bit of
detail and texture
imagine eventually eventually in the
long run that we have skyscrapers coming
out of the ground here as well this is
the centerpiece and we have other
skyscrapers coming out it could be
absolutely
amazing it's unfortunate really that
mumbo is away at the moment because i
could really use an archibarro to help
me here so i'm making a water elevator
and for the most part that's really
simple all you do
is build up this one tube all the way to
the top and fill it with bubbles but i
wanted to create a proper elevator
system with redstone
and i wanted it so that you clicked a
button on the floor that you wanted to
go to
and you'd go up the tube and pistons
would push you out but that sounds a lot
easier than it actually is
and let me show you why so this is a
little test world that i was messing
around with for a while there's even an
old build of mine over there that's the
circle that i just built on top of the
base this is where i come just to mess
around with a few ideas so this is the
the basic concept that i came up with
this is
please do not judge my redstone it's
terrible the idea was that a perfectly
timed button to level one which you
click it you go inside and then pistons
push you out like so so a redstone
signal goes all the way up the top it's
delayed enough just enough so that it
hits you just as you come up here the
problem is
when these pistons push the blocks
inside the water
it then cancels
the water block source so this is now
flowing water and not an actual source
block which is a problem you see when i
add another source block here
the bubbles continue all the way to the
top now if my design was to work
properly
there would be several buttons you know
one two and three and you click i want
to go to level one you click that bush
off it goes and it pushes you out at
level one let's pretend that's here and
then if you wanted to go to level two
you hit bush level two button and it
goes all the way up and it pushes you
out when you get to this level here
obviously you can just walk out at the
level but it's it'd be so much cooler if
it was
properly designed with redstone and i
have a feeling it is possible to i'm not
you know i don't know redstone enough to
do it so my initial thought was i need
to make these water source blocks again
and i thought oh that's easy i'll use
dispensers in order to do that so i
tried filling these up with buckets
and that didn't really work either
so
overall i need mumbo's help to
i don't even know if this is possible
but i would like a redstone guy's help
to see if it's possible to make a
redstone elevator that if you click the
level you want to go to you go hop click
the button you hop in and 99 times out
of 100 it'll push you out at the right
level see that works but then
it ruins it you see it ruins it it's no
longer pushing me up meaning any layer
that is above that one would then no
longer work
which kind of sucks
so instead we're just going to do the
old-fashioned way of well i say
old-fashioned it's still brand new with
these water source blocks these water
elevators they are possibly my favorite
thing that have been added to minecraft
in a very long time i also could look on
youtube to see if there are redstone
tutorials on this thing but i kind of
prefer to learn myself and preferably
get the help of someone that knows what
they're doing and we can come up with
something truly truly unique
so we're up to the first layer here
once we're in
get rid of this bottom one
pop the soul sand in and up we go oh
it's so quick oh this could be so
satisfying
that gives us access to the first level
but i actually want to get access to the
all the way to the top
so i might make a separate tube or i
could just
i could just keep using this one to be
honest
oh we've got a long way up to the top
oh this is this isn't safe oh no no no
no i'm gonna die oh this is uh oh this
is this is not good this is not good
this is not good this is not good
safety safety this is i need to light
this up
is there anywhere safe
half a heart
okay not safe not safe at all we're
going outside and we're gonna fly like a
normal person for now but that does go
to show that these towers are ideal
candidates for a mob farm oh boy
no
[Laughter]
is it going to keep going
i really wanted
i would have tried it down
no
oh
bye-bye trident
he's climbed all the way to the top and
i can't get him
i've never seen a spider do that before
i've never seen a spider do that
how weird
there we go
oh no no
oh thank goodness there was water there
right let's get out of here
oh oh that was so skillfully done i feel
like i could decorate it more but i
think this is definitely just gonna be a
temporary one until we can figure out
this redstone thing if it even exists
so i'm actually thinking that when we
actually make it because of the odd
shape of this one and i was thinking
that these two could become mob farms i
was thinking the elevator could be in
this one here just because it's so
square it actually fits what an elevator
should be you click the button and then
you go shooting up to the top i think
that's at least my idea at the moment
the only thing i'm wondering to do is
like what do i do with this entrance
here because there is a door there and
you can get in if you're a bit sneaky
about it but
yeah i might have to do a little bit of
working things out but let's experience
this shall we
you do go really fast
i mean i can make this way more
interesting to look at well to be honest
with you if it's the inside of a mob
farm it would be really interesting to
go up that anyway just seeing all the
mobs that are spawn
look at all this unused space i bet
there's creatures up there and
everywhere
so we actually now have a way up here
that doesn't take any time at all
seeing as this episode has turned out to
be a bit shorter and it involves a lot
more of my sort of chore type jobs i
guess i'm going to continue in that
frame of mind and i'll go over some of
the plans that i had in mind i really
wish you could fly up these there must
be a way to fly up
oh
oh my goodness there is a way
oh i've been going up that the long way
this whole time anyway so we're up here
for a good reason we're gonna go and fly
a little bit further out from the pigman
farm because what i want to show you
today is something that i saw on simply
sarc's video and
there's a lot of options to do and i'm
not entirely sure what i'm going to do
with it yet
but i have a feeling it's going to come
in useful for sure so if we want a quick
color i've got an empty map here and
that's going to fill it up you can see
that it's got this weird pattern on it
and if we put that in an item frame
that's going to come up as one of those
so now that we've got this map let's
head back to the base and i'll try and
explain what i plan to do with this
um
where's the pig
where's the pig man farm
uh oh i'm pretty sure this is my life
now i don't know where i am
i thought it was this way
i can't find the pigman farm anywhere i
didn't fly that far out did i
and i'm wasting rockets like i always do
i feel like the further i fly the worse
it gets yep we gotta turn around
wait what's that
is there a hulk silenced
what
oh my goodness
what is going on here
what is this
what have i stumbled across
i heard i i'm hearing withers how do
these magicians break bedrock
how have they tamed the wither i'm
scared but i've at least i've found a
way out
where is the oh the withers in there
oh he's trapped in the bedrock
oh that's that genuinely scared the life
out of me
well we're leaving as soon as possible
there we are i recognize this this is
someone's project and there we have it
the gr the the g tower i don't know what
we're gonna call it but it looks it
looks pretty cool these towers are
mighty impressive it just doesn't look
quite right yet don't you don't need to
go and tell me in the comments i know
i just don't have the resources to
finish it yet
geez all i wanted to do was make an item
frame
right so the idea is if you pop one of
these out and i've got a spare item
frame this covers the entire thing right
now imagine that this was all one color
in fact you don't need to imagine it
because i'm going to show you an idea
that i had the concept is on the floor
you put a lot of white concrete powder
or whatever this is just what's readily
available for me this is probably what
i'm going to use you cover the floor in
it and then you use a map to create all
one standard color
and then you take this and you put it
inside an item frame and i was messing
around with this for a while now if you
use glowstone it means that the entire
thing is lit up
and i also figured out that item frames
don't get destroyed if you use them on a
fence gate meaning
i could create a quote red pill room
like matrix style
where you fall down a hole
and end up in pure
white this is i'm moving around you can
see my my fists like moving around i
don't know what's up what's down what's
left what's right if i press f look
that's just it's just pure color
but if i turn around
wait
there's meant to be a door in here
where's the oh oh there's the
i got myself so lost look how
how magical does this look and i was
thinking in hermitcraft if i can get my
hands on just one of these maps then i
can create a room like this to mess with
the hermits
imagine that i could coax one of them
into this room
and have them standing in here with me
it would just look so peculiar so i'm
thinking i'm gonna make one of these
rooms now this room isn't actually very
big it's only three blocks wide but you
can't tell it looks like it goes on for
infinity the idea would be then to have
like a little corridor now this is the
biggest that the corridor can get
because after a while
the maps stop rendering so if they
started here
they have to walk towards the door and
it just looks there's just something
about this sort of effect that has me
absolutely amazed and then you go
through the door and you make it out the
other side but this is what this room
looks like it's not quite as long as
this this was just me messing about
but you can see here there you go that's
the end of it
so this is how big that room is but it
looked like it went on for infinity so
i'm hoping i can make something like
this in hermitcraft using the map trick
and i don't know doing a bit of
bamboozling imagine okay for a really
really elaborate thing
if we created
a maze made out of it so you could have
from the outside
it might look like a bunch of these
three by
i don't know let's say three by ten you
have a bunch of corridors one going that
way one going this way some of them like
the floor can fall through like here and
you go up down a level it could just be
the most baffling thing and you could
have doors just everywhere doors
everywhere and you open it and it tells
you something and it's like you know
wrong way or oh it could just be the
best maze ever but for the time being i
just want to use use it to freak out
people a little bit it is so weird the
difficulty of course is getting my hands
on 256
stacks yes stacks of white concrete
powder now obviously i've been getting
white concrete powder for a while now so
that's not really an issue i've got
plenty of bone meal gravel sand
but do i really want to spend
that much resources
that much sand gravel and bone meal to
create
one map
one map i could do it probably for free
if i just did the map over the water and
just made it blue
but something something about the white
room has me feeling all matrixy inside
so you're gonna have to let me know if
it's worth my time anyway that's it for
today's episode thank you very very much
for watching and i'm sorry it's not the
usual green episode i'm afraid it is a
bit more of a chore but some people did
say they wanted to see me do the actual
building a bit more rather than just
showing off progress so do let me know
what you think and thank you thank you
thank you very very much for watching
good
bye